<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on jens.lordén.dev</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on jens.lordén.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on switching to vim bindings</title>
      <link>/posts/my-initial-thoughts-after-swtiching-to-vim-motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 23:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-initial-thoughts-after-swtiching-to-vim-motions/</guid>
      <description>Even though I have been using spacemacs as my daily driver for coding and writing blog posts like this one I have been using the traditional emacs keybindings. Going from &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; keybindings to emacs felt like a great productivity boost, this made me wonder if maybe there is an even better option. Enter vim keybindings, in this post I will explain my experience switching to vim keybindings and what my thoughts are about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop procrastinating with note taking and start org-roam</title>
      <link>/posts/stop-procrastinating-with-note-taking-and-start-org-roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/stop-procrastinating-with-note-taking-and-start-org-roam/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t use to like taking notes but now I like it. When reading something interesting in a book I will take a pause, write it down, or if I encounter a bug while programming I will document how I solved this bug . The thought is that if I can organize all my knowledge into a &amp;ldquo;second brain&amp;rdquo; then that will allow me to be more productive.
However I did not end up being more productive, in fact I suddenly got even less stuff done because I spent too much time writing and organizing my notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why i like dbt and why you should too</title>
      <link>/posts/why-i-like-dbt-any-why-you-should-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-i-like-dbt-any-why-you-should-too/</guid>
      <description>Dbt (or data build tool) transforms the way you work with sql, if you are someone like me that comes from a software engineering background then you will feel at home with the dbt workflow. So let&amp;rsquo;s get to it, first what is dbt?
Dbt is an open-source command line tool that helps analysts and engineers transform data in their warehouse more effectively.
Ok this is what dbt is according to wikipedia, but lets try to get a little better understanding then that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog index</title>
      <link>/blog-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-index/</guid>
      <description>Index Hello, and welcome to my corner on the internet. My name is Jens Lordén and I am a software engineer/ML Engineer/MLOps Enineer/Game developer located in Stockholm, Sweden.
I currently work as a MLOps Engineer at Tele2, formerly a machine learning engineer formerly a game developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
